<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>net.techtimejourney.SpinFM</id>
  <name>Spin FM</name>
  <summary>Lightweight tabbed file management for Linux</summary>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0-or-later</project_license>
  <description>
    <p>Spin FM is a compact Qt file manager with tabbed navigation, selected-file MIME and metadata reporting, drag and drop, Trash support, configurable themes, removable USB device controls, and an embedded audio player.</p>
    <p>Long-running copy, move, delete, storage, and device operations run outside the interface thread to keep navigation responsive.</p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">net.techtimejourney.SpinFM.desktop</launchable>
  <provides>
    <binary>spin-fm</binary>
  </provides>
  <categories>
    <category>System</category>
    <category>FileTools</category>
    <category>FileManager</category>
  </categories>
  <releases>
    <release version="2.6.20" date="2026-07-19">
      <description>
        <p>Makes file and recursive folder sizes reliably visible through direct tab-view click integration, a status field that yields to operation messages, and MIME-failure isolation.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.19" date="2026-07-19">
      <description>
        <p>Unifies startup in main.py and repairs python3-magic MIME detection across supported binding APIs.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.18" date="2026-07-19">
      <description>
        <p>Preserves executable permissions across GitHub Actions artifact downloads with a tar-based workflow, automatic mode repair, and checkout-independent source ZIP permissions.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.17" date="2026-07-19">
      <description>
        <p>Uses one application-level Qt event filter for selected-file metadata in every current and future tab, with drag-release protection and no per-view signal registration.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.16" date="2026-07-19">
      <description>
        <p>Connects the independent selected-file size, modification-time, and MIME module to the real click signal in existing and newly opened tabs while leaving the core window and tabs implementation unchanged.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.15" date="2026-07-19">
      <description>
        <p>Restores selected-file path, size, modification time, and MIME reporting through an independent bounded module.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.14" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Keeps every Trash-location row on the active application theme before selection, including USB and mounted-volume Trash.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.13" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Removes a duplicate Ctrl+T action so New Tab has one unambiguous window-level shortcut.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.12" date="2026-07-17">
      <description>
        <p>Adds a large full-path Trash chooser, keeps F9 mount actions visible with remembered sizing, defaults first-run icons to Adwaita, and tightens worker and cleanup lifecycles.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.11" date="2026-07-17">
      <description>
        <p>Makes Trash navigation and emptying explicit, changes local drag-and-drop into confirmed moves with conflict prompts, and documents the supported PyQt 5 source dependencies.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.8" date="2026-07-17">
      <description>
        <p>Adds native MPRIS desktop-player registration, complete wrapped names, LWM Dark and Graphite themes, and a simplified cache-free Debian build interface.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.7" date="2026-07-17">
      <description>
        <p>Makes Alt+P deterministic across delayed multimedia backends, adds routed audio shortcuts, and standardizes GPL-2.0-or-later release metadata.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.6" date="2026-07-16">
      <description>
        <p>Hardens cache-free Debian and source release automation and removes legacy artifacts.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.5" date="2026-07-16">
      <description>
        <p>Makes source, test, release, and Debian workflows cache-free by default and adds deterministic source-archive validation.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.4" date="2026-07-16">
      <description>
        <p>Removes Python-index packaging, modernizes direct Debian installation, and hardens optional Wayland_OSD discovery and failure isolation.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.3" date="2026-07-16">
      <description>
        <p>Restores double-click activation, expands the seekable audio player, and adds optional failure-isolated Wayland_OSD feedback.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.2" date="2026-07-15">
      <description>
        <p>Adds Ctrl+Up parent navigation and a lazy-loaded, theme-aware player that starts common audio files on activation.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.1" date="2026-07-15">
      <description>
        <p>Stability release with safe command launching, coalesced storage scans, rollback-safe overwrites, and expanded runtime tests.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.0" date="2026-07-15">
      <description>
        <p>Production-focused release with asynchronous operations, bounded caches, a refreshed interface, and Debian packaging.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <url type="homepage">https://techtimejourney.net/</url>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
</component>
